Hi, my name is Shoe Nice Shoe Nice, aka
Shoe Nice 22.
A lot of people think I'm a complete
idiot, but actually I'm a professional
idiot with decades of experience.
On your marks, get set, Shoe Nice.
And I just opened up my throat.
and just something happens and I just know
it's like Evel Knievel jumping over them
20 buses.
He knows he can die but once he gets over
it it's epic for life.
Here's to you.
People must think I'm nuts.
I'm in the right place at the right time
to do whatever I want.
I don't want to be President of the United
States.
I'll save the world from the number one
YouTube channel.
It's a nice day today, a nice day to go
swimming.
Maybe we'll go swimming later on.
All I do is travel around the world, you
know.
My family threw me out two years ago
because they just didn't understand my
YouTube, you know, career and what
it's all about.
Always seems like I stay in a hotel near a
cemetery.
I don't know why, but like the last four
hotels I've been in, I come out in the
morning, it's daylight, there's a
cemetery.
I don't know if God's trying to tell me
something, but either way, Lake George,
New York.
Just spreading the word.
We had a great house, great family.
My father and mom had me and my two
brothers.
Really good times and then just things
started changing in the house.
My father wasn't home every night and
eventually there was a for sale sign out
and we went from like a nice...
everybody had their own bedroom to like a
one bedroom with my mom you know who
literally just started drinking
from all the problems.
It's been about 35 years nothing's
changed.
We just bounced from apartment to
apartment because me and my brothers were
so crazy that literally landlords would
just
say you're a great lady but your your kids
are psycho.
What's going on buddy?
I used to live here as a kid.
Now I'm famous on YouTube so we're doing a
documentary about my life.
My name is Chris by the way.
Mike, nice to meet you.
You own this property?
Yeah, it's my grandmother's.
Oh, okay.
She's owned it since.
Yeah, we played around a garage.
I just always remember we weren't supposed
to go somewhere and finally the landlord
Maybe it's the one who owned it and it
just said listen you got three
great sons, but they're animals you got to
move out We weren't bad kids, but we just
like spray-painted the sides of people's
houses.
We don't know why we were only seven But
never did anything bad.
It was nice meeting you.
All right.
Take it easy, man.
Oh Yo neighborhood Never changes.
As far back as I can remember, I just was
always the kid on the playground or
outside in the yard.
And just everybody in the neighborhood
knew I would eat crazy things.
I was eating grass at first and I'd
swallow pebbles.
In my home economics class, I just started
eating the salt, the baking soda, and
actually it became such a trending
thing in home economics that they always
knew that our group would never be able to
finish the cake or the muffins or whatever
because
I already ate half the ingredients.
And then it became just like something
that I knew I could make money off of.
I got three guys from England that don't
believe I can drink three bottles of
Budweiser with the tops on them in under a
minute.
No hands.
On your mark, get set, go That's it.
That's it.
Two nights.
So I was in high school, like, with gangs,
and, like, the principal got his ear half
cut off, so I knew it was time to go.
My mom said, if you want to quit high
school, you have to join the Army.
And I said, no problem.
So I joined the Army.
I did my basic training.
I did all this other stuff.
Eventually, you know, Baghdad was being
bombed in 1991.
I'm watching it with my roommates.
Wow, man, they're tearing shit up.
The phone rings.
Is this Christopher Thomas Shuey,
097-BB-BB-BB?
So I knew once they sent my social
security number, they were coming off the
IRR list.
So I went out there.
That was food supply.
I basically just fed all the troops food
and water as they came through.
One day there was a sandstorm, and I found
these two little kids buried in this
little sand dune.
I gave them some ravioli and did a few
more beef stew.
You can see just the energy come back in
them too, and just things like that are
why I want to make sure no
kid goes to bed hungry anymore in the
world.
The YouTube community has allowed me to
take that next level into what I've always
believed in, stopping global hunger
for good.
I'm gonna explain to you something to
everybody and this is the way it is.
My mom told me that someday, Chris, you're
gonna save the world and she knew it too
because that's what I'm gonna do.
Actually, my son signed me up for YouTube
when he was eight years old.
I didn't even know that you could have a
YouTube channel.
So he was actually the one that signed me
up.
And then he said, Dad, the only way you're
really going to let people know that
you're on YouTube is to join Facebook.
So once I posted a YouTube vid and it was
40 views the next day, I was sold.
I just knew that was the best advertising
for whatever you wanted to sell or believe
in.
When I first did YouTube, I just did a
joke.
It built up.
and people were suggesting, why don't you
do what you did in high school at the
cafeteria table?
You used to take the toilet paper, the
napkins, and you'd eat it all.
I go, okay, I'll do that.
So I did a three-part series where I ate a
whole roll of 1,000 sheets of toilet paper
in like 10 minutes.
That literally is what blew me up.
And all my eating stunts after Elmer's
Glil were all requests from my fans.
Go to my buddy Nathan's diner, Wake and
Bacon.
I was just here the other day.
I set a new challenge for his menu.
Hey, there's my buddy Ian.
We know everybody in the town.
How you doing Ian?
We're gonna come have some breakfast.
How you doing?
Awesome.
Alright.
Look at that Which is a nice drive, I'm
just kidding.
around the town knows us around here but
we don't play games hey everyone shoonites
again well basically
this is my first interview with a famous
youtuber blazed 420 otherwise
known as Ian Dude's no joke, helped me out
a lot, he's my friend.
I met Shoe Nice and I liked his stuff
immediately and then I started watching
his blog TV
and live and then I found out that he was
in Balls' spot off
or something.
He's walking down Lake George the road and
I'm like Shoe Nice and we basically
immediately hit it off.
I have a separate YouTube, it's called
Glazed 420.
I do things like working out because I do
calisthenics.
So I do like a minute and a half
handstand.
I do a bunch of pull-ups.
I do a bunch of goofy videos.
I have one that's pretty viral where I'm
getting tased by a cop at a fish show.
The video went viral.
It has like about 40,000 views.
Hey, I'm too nice again.
Well, basically, I missed the polar bear
club the other night.
Oh, I gotta leave my shirt on.
Oh, boy.
Woo-hoo.
Oh,
I can't do it.
You
do.
Oh my god, my room keys, bro, are in my
pants, bro.
I've known Chris for years, on and off for
11 years, and he just recently started
staying at the motel and telling me of his
success on YouTube.
People just living at the hotel and it
don't happen too often.
We're against it.
But Chris can stay here anytime right now.
He'll bring a smile to my face when I have
a bad day.
You can't go wrong with that.
With Shoenice, his style on YouTube, he
likes it to be very simple.
He doesn't want any intro with the
letterheads and all that.
He wants it simple and down to the point.
Right, right, right.
Let's eat some glue today.
Hey everyone, Shoe Nice again.
Well basically you're probably wondering
why I'm wearing a microphone right now.
Well the Vice Documentary crew, they
actually showed up here today and they're
videotaping me right now.
And we got my man Dan, he's got a bottle
of wood glue and he's going to open up the
top and he's going to pour it in
my mouth.
Somebody's actually testing it out.
It's glue I love you bro On your mark, get
set, don't kill me, shoe
knives
I mean, oh man, not in the face bro, not
Francis is gonna want my job.
I gotta go out of here.
It's coming out of my nose, hold on.
The water's for pussies, but the glue
isn't.
Alright man, let's finish this up, bro.
I say that's good enough.
I say that's good enough, don't you?
Time.
Thank you Well, that's how we do a shoe
nice fit.
I'm gonna clean myself up.
How you doing?
Either way, basically what I do is
medicinal marijuana.
I got Crohn's disease.
So either way, I just, this is what I do
for my medications.
Instead of spending thousands of dollars
on medicines that give you more side
effects than the actual Crohn's disease.
And I've been in remission for 25 years
just smoking something that comes out of
the ground.
So either way, how you doing?
A lot of people probably don't like me
smoking weed and doing videos for teenage
kids, but I'd rather see a kid smoke a
tree than get
wrapped around one.
Let's get rid of the alcohol, you know
what I mean?
But then the prisons would be only about
30% full.
Here's one of my secrets.
Cranberry juice solves all problems.
All right, all right.
Let's get this loaded up to YouTube.
Vice Documentary on location.
When I started YouTube, I never had an
enemy in my life.
So I don't know what it was like to be
like a Rush Limbaugh.
Like all these people just hate ya.
A lot of people argue between each other
on my comment boards.
I mean, I'll go back the next day and
they've literally argued for hours on end
over the most stupidest things.
Let me just get a feel for what the people
are saying in the comment board.
I don't think it's going to be anything
other than, oh my god, this is incredible.
Badass shoe.
This is the only time I'm going to say
first is best.
Love the behind the scenes shoe.
Nice.
Vice has sunk to a new low.
Whatever.
La la.
These are just people that fight over
first, actually.
You look so fucking baked, haha, awesome,
haha, it sounds like you're really
enjoying it.
I just think that there's a lot of people
out there that are just jealous of me.
They just, they want to sit at home and do
what they do.
I get bottles of liquor sent to me and I
get drunk and I get paid for it.
It's fun to troll.
You want one of these?
You want to eat one?
Really?
You're gonna eat one?
You're gonna eat one with me?
I'm not opening it.
Oh you got sugar porn on your lap.
I'm going like this.
Oh you can't eat them it keeps all the
sugar together.
Some people have made these fake rest in
peace videos like my brother died trying
to do and it hurts me.
You know I'm saving a billion children
before my heart stops beating so if we
lose one to a tampon
stunt I just call it collateral damage to
be honest with you.
Everybody tries to impersonate their hero
sometime and I just have to have over
5,000 parody vids of
people either hating me, imitating me,
attempting my stunts, just shouting me
out, or literally they just want to find
me and kill me.
I don't understand.
I took all the beer out of my fridge on
4th of July and I went straight for six
years.
Then I started doing YouTube.
I was still straight.
My ex-wife couldn't handle the fame so
she's like you gotta go and I moved out to
the garage.
You can see how I had some garage vids and
and then I just eventually just left the
property and I knew
I wasn't putting my son to bed that night
so time to drink.
On your mark, get set...
That's the only reason why I put the
bottle down, is for family.
So without them, it was chaotic again.
But I was homeless for a while.
I did matchbook stunts.
On your mark, get set, shoot nice, hard.
Look at this
town.
Ah, hee-haw bitches.
Every bar banned me.
I mean, I literally couldn't go anywhere.
I met this hotel owner that was rehabbing
all these hotels.
He actually fed me, gave me a place to do
my laundry.
He desperately needs something.
He's a veterinarian.
And then I helped him a little bit.
And after that, I saw him on YouTube.
And then now, he came back and he said he
wants to spend some time in Lake George
and he wants to rent
a room from me.
him out.
It was nice to see him again.
Yeah, he borrowed my car, went to the
store, and comes back and it's full with
gas and gave me money and this and that.
I mean, he's got a big heart.
He likes to make these.
Basically, I'm going to save the whole
country of Africa, so we're going to start
practicing doing donation drive-bys.
These people have never seen us before
behind us, and we're going to go surprise
this one lady with a $20 bill.
You're not out.
I make money off of Google.
I know what it's like to be homeless.
I'm not saying you are, but what we do is
we help out people.
Okay?
All I had was a 20 on me, but this guy
Ian, my cameraman, is very friendly.
I've been on Tosh.0, World's Dumbest.
I mean, I'm just a crazy fella.
Hey, we were so poor growing up.
My mom used to say, you better finish
everything on your plate.
There's people right now starving in the
living room.
Get it?
I think my mom was just a woman that just
was too young to have three sons on her
own.
She just, you know, eventually alcohol
took over and literally it would be like
she would go out
on a Friday night, she wouldn't want to,
you know, forget about her kids, but she
would go into a blackout,
obviously, you know, go go somewhere other
than her home and then the neighbors were
wondering when she'd pull in like you know
the next
afternoon and I always was able to suffice
when we didn't have food in the house you
know
if you didn't have a Miracle Whip sandwich
I just take some sheets off the toilet
paper roll because really it feels
I think I still do it to this day it fills
your belly but you know my father
eventually came and got us and
time See, I don't like to hang out with
drunk people.
My mother was a chronic alcoholic.
She was a great lady, but when I found her
dead at 56 on her living room floor, I
knew she was out of her misery
because she lived off of vodka.
I guess that's where I get my liquor
slamming stunts from, you know?
My mom always had that big bottle of
vodka, you know, right underneath the
kitchen
sink next to the dish soap.
I thought it was normal to go to eighth
grade in a blackout by lunch.
I mean, we just used to take the whole
glass of vodka to the bus stop.
We'd all pass it around and go to school.
It'll catch up to you someday.
It'll catch up to me.
They sent me a bottle of Devil's Spring,
160 proof, 30 proof less, so...
Now what I'm going to do is talk to you
before I slam this bottle.
Nothing's fake about this, I just have a
really crazy tolerance for liquor.
The Devil Springs was kind of freaky, 160
proof.
My friends were there, I kind of like, was
lethargic.
and passing out and they couldn't wake me
up so I woke up actually with a tube down
my throat it's the only time I've ever had
my stomach pumped
and be honest with you I was mad because I
didn't have insurance and I knew that tube
down my throat was about a $400 procedure
Alcohol leads to bad stuff.
The only two times I ever smoked crack in
my life was when I was drunk.
I would never even think about walking
down the street looking for a bump at 4 in
the morning going like this.
When Shoenice chugs bottles of liquor, I
feel concerned for his health.
I don't want to see the guy end up dying
from one of his drinking stunts.
And I showed my concern and a bunch of
people on Facebook and YouTube have showed
the concern.
So he did one stunt with a bottle of
Everclear to end all the drinking stunts.
He defeats death in a way, you know what I
mean?
Because some of the stuff, normal people
would die from it.
And it's just like people like that
about...
Death-defying things and like wow he must
be some kind of mutant you know what I
mean there's something special
about Shoe Nice where he can handle that
kind of stuff you know.
It's hard it's hard for anybody to hear
but then there's smokers and stuff like
that you know it's life is full of choices
and he's making a choice and
do I agree with it no but it's getting him
somewhere isn't it it's I don't know.
Would I do it?
No.
I mean but people do anything for money
they say so.
Maybe he's getting a little money out of
it and that's why he's eating glue and
tampons.
everything else.
And what I do is I'm basically trying to
figure out who can really handle, you
know, being a part of my
revolution.
I got Muslims hanging out with, you know,
whites from southern Alabama.
I mean, I've literally had people come in
and go, Shoe Nights, you saved me from a
suicide, you brought our couple, you know,
you brought us back together as a couple,
and it's just, you know, you're in our
lives now, don't ever leave, stop all the
craziness, because you will save the
world.
of people's higher power.
They're antidepressant and it's just like,
where is it going to lead to?
Scares me sometimes.
But I mean, he does it what he does it, he
does it.
And I think that's what people looking at
it now, that what he's doing is
amazing.
Yeah.
I'm hoping I can stop global hunger in
three years because I'm getting tired.
But if I die, I know that there'll be
people to carry on.
I'll be a better martyr and a better human
on this planet.
That's a guarantee.
All right.
I own this town.
You heard me.
Trying to play dead in the cemetery.
I'm right.
I'm not dead.
Hi Aaron, it's Shoe Nice.
Great job on the documentary.
I loved everything.
One thing I would like to take back that I
said, though, is that if a child died
imitating one of my stunts on YouTube,
it would be collateral damage towards my
revolution.
Actually, I would like to take that back.
That would be devastating to me, just for
me to even think that I had any, you know,
possibility in the, you
know, way of somebody dying.
So, yeah.
I appreciate you doing my life story.
It should help me out a lot with my hunger
campaign.
But that was just the one thing I really
wish I could stick my foot in my mouth on,
is that comment about collateral
damage for a teenage kid to die imitating
one of my stunts.
Because that would literally break my
heart.
Okay, thanks, Aaron.
But if you keep it in, that's no problem
either.
Documentary's a documentary.
Ba-ha-ha-hee-ha.
Thank you.